<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>catalogs | Eleonora Alei</title><link>https://eleonoraalei.github.io/tag/catalogs/</link><atom:link href="https://eleonoraalei.github.io/tag/catalogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>catalogs</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://eleonoraalei.github.io/media/icon_hue13ec9768477f6aaf9b00b431f1b1817_1052_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>catalogs</title><link>https://eleonoraalei.github.io/tag/catalogs/</link></image><item><title>The all-sky PLATO input catalogue</title><link>https://eleonoraalei.github.io/publication/2021-aa-653-a-98-m/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eleonoraalei.github.io/publication/2021-aa-653-a-98-m/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Exo-MerCat</title><link>https://eleonoraalei.github.io/project/exo-mercat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eleonoraalei.github.io/project/exo-mercat/</guid><description>&lt;p>The search for exoplanets (i.e. planets that orbit other stars in our Galaxy other than the Sun) has been growing as a bold branch of astrophysics for the past two decades, with more than 5000 confirmed exoplanets known to date. Surveys and missions reveal day by day new candidates and provide us insight concerning their orbital and bulk parameters, and the properties of their host stars. We are now aware of the fact that exoplanets differ from one another in many of these physical parameters, and in the future we should be able to fully understand the diversity of their chemical compositions, atmospheric processes, internal structures and formation conditions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During my Ph.D., I wrote a Python script that compiles the Exoplanet Merged Catalog (Exo-MerCat). a Python code that collects and selects the most precise measurement for all interesting planetary and orbital parameters of all Super Earths included in the three major exoplanets online databases: NASA Exoplanet Archive, Exoplanet Orbit Database, and Exoplanet Encyclopaedia. By downloading all source files from the three catalogs using VO ConeSearch connections and considering user preferences through a Graphic User Interface, it creates a merged catalog and generates automatically all standard plots.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>